**Imad Ali** 

Phone: (347) 824 1258

Email: imadmali@gmail.com

Website: http://www.imadali.net

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/imadmali

GitHub https://github.com/imadmali

#### **Profile**

Experienced Data Science professional with expertise in **R**, **Python**, **SQL**, **Git**, **Bash**, **Stata**, **Mathematica**, and **AWS**. Fluent in **Stan** (an implementation of Bayesian statistical inference in R) and have a working knowledge of **Theano** (deep learning Python library). Exceptional communicator to individuals with quantitative and non-quantitative backgrounds. Current research involves Bayesian inference and computational methods in Statistics. Areas of proficiency include:

Bayesian Statistics

• Machine Learning

Econometrics

Data Mining

Hierarchical Modeling

• Institutional Research

#### **Professional Experience**

# The New School, Data Analyst, Provost's Office - Planning and Analytics

Jun 2015 - Jan 2016

- Developed logistic regression models to determine the effect of financial aid on student enrolment for graduate programs.
- Worked closely on developing data analytic and data management tools with the Director of Business Intelligence and Associate Provost.
- Identified flaws in existing data processing software and updated Python dictionaries to amend these flaws.

### Al Jazeera, Media Data Consultant, Al Jazeera Sports

Aug 2015

 Provided insight on how to compare World Wrestling Entertainment's popularity against peer sports franchises and entertainment companies (http://bit.ly/1P8xtCV).

### New York Office of the Attorney General, Statistician, Civil Rights Bureau

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

- Developed econometric models using Stata and R to model bank behavior in New York State using least squares, weighted least squares, and logistic regression models.
- Implemented odds ratio analyses and Fisher's exact test using Python to determine discriminatory lending practices by banks.
- Presented a business case to the Bureau Chief on the implementation of descriptive and inferential statistics in the department, and the availability and use of data relevant to the bureau's docket.

#### Scottish Government, Assistant Economist, Office of the Chief Economic Adviser

Sep 2013 - Mar 2014

- Collaborated with statisticians to update GDP, productivity, and labor market statistics for the First Minister and Finance Minister.
- Led the department on weekly and monthly economic briefing (including ad hoc requests).
- Responsible for delivering and updating a weekly economic performance brief to the First Minister, containing
  information from various government departments.

- Prepared a response to a Parliamentary Question on the performance of Scottish exports on behalf of the Finance Minister (http://bit.ly/29X5SsW).
- Coordinated the report on Scotland's economic performance for the European Commission.
- Redesigned the departments briefing in order to meet Parliamentary standards and ensured briefing was prepared accurately and delivered on time.

# **Academic Experience**

# Columbia University, Teaching Assistant, Bayesian Statistics

Jan 2016 - May 2016

Teaching assistant for Bayesian Statistics for the Social Sciences taught by Dr Benjamin Goodrich.

### The New School, Research Assistant, Item Analysis

Jan 2016 - May 2016

- Prepared an item analysis for an undergraduate Quantitative Reasoning course, including statistics on test reliability and discrimination.
- Developed teaching material on Vector Calculus.

#### The New School, Teaching Fellow, Quantitative Reasoning

Aug 2015 - Dec 2015

- Taught a core course on applied mathematics and statistics to a class of over 20 students.
- Topics included Financial Mathematics, Statistical Inference, Probability Theory, and Data Analysis.

# **Relevant Courses**

•	Neural Networks and Deep Learning	(Columbia University)
•	Bayesian Data Analysis	(Columbia University)
•	Data Mining	(Columbia University)
•	Applied Econometrics	(New York University)
•	Panel Data Analysis	(New York University)

# **Education**

Columbia University, New York, USA

MA Statistics (2018)

Edinburgh University, Scotland, UK

MS Economics (2013)

Leeds University, England, UK

BA Joint Honors Economics and Politics (2012)